Guide to the Barbara L. Kevles Collection on Gordon Parks M1409
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Parks interview & correspondence, Working Woman (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Note by Barbara Kevles about sophistication of crowd in which Gene & Gordon Parks move so that color is not an issue and the two of them don't think of each other as black or Chinese. 29 pp. typed Gene Parks interview: Gene Parks: Scenes From A Marriage (revised) Second Carbon Copy The Introduction and Interview incorporate all changes requested in Text Changes from Discussion with Gene Parks (unsolicited). Fifth page noted above. Contains additional hand-written editorial comments by Gene Parks. Barbara Kevles' hand-written note on coral stickum, "Geno's hand-written comments which I ignored." Carbon copy of letter from Barbara Kevles to Gordon Parks, dated March 21, 1977. It's a cover letter accompanying a payment of $450 to Gordon Parks minus Kevles' 10% agent fee for his photographs of Gene Parks published in the magazine. Kevles emphasizes how she got the magazine to more than double its usual photographer's fee of $200 for Gordon's photos. The letter concludes, "I am honored that your photographs are appearing with my interview." Letter from Barbara Kevles to Gordon Parks dated January 25, 1977. It confirms the Working Woman $500 fee for Parks' photos of his wife and Kevles' agent fee. It concludes,"...It was marvelous seeing you and Gene Saturday. As you know, I like you both very, very much." The letter includes and invoice for Parks' photos sent to Working Woman. Gene Parks: Delivery WORKING WOMAN 7/19/76
- Village Voice May 10, 1976 Arts Section Cover Story (Box 2, Folder 11)
  "Gordon Parks: 'I Don't Make Black Exploitation Films." The published article is a no-holds-barred chronicle of Gordon's fight against Paramount's marketing of his film Leadbelly as a Blaxploitation film. Gordon is up against studio bookings in rundown inner city theaters, a tasteless ad of an ape-like hero, prostitute and a fight, and Paramount's refusal to contact big city critics about his film's premiere in their towns.
- Cineaste (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Gordon Parks, recorded (Box 2, Folder 13)
  20 minutes of tape on 5" Reel of questions and Gordon's answer at Philadelphia Philmfest April 6, '76. Gordon's Taped answers are crystal clear sound bites. Gordon gives totally uncensored views on black actors, his directing style, Leadbelly's personal meaning for him, Paramount's distribution tactics, his photography's influence, his camera style, hollywood prejudice, his mandate for a black crew, his film's benefits for blacks. Gordon Parks selves into where he grew up, how he worked with black people who had never worked in front of cameras, views of how much a director directs. His next projects including a Concerto for Cello and Orchestra. The symbolic meaning of Leadbelly's life to him as an artist, his catching a Leadbelly performance in 1949 - 2 months before Leadbelly's death. Why he didn't use Leadbelly's own recordings in the film as an insight into Leadbelly's treatment by his times and the smash hit of his song Goodnight Irene 8 months following his death and Leadbelly's view of his legacy and Park's. His problems with Paramount's distribution of his film and his views without a black VIP insider the film never would have been made. Why he won't make fast buck films. The influence of his photography, particularly fashion photography for Vogue, on how he shoots films. Views on what he searches for in shots -- beauty vs. truth. His relationship to cameraman, how much he frames shot, shots he took in film. How Ken Hyman. Pres. of Warner Brothers 7 Arts, broke down Hollywood prejudices to get him his first film project, Learning Tree, which he wrote, scored and produced from his book. His mandate for a black film crew and its fulfillment on Learning Tree, on Leadbelly, sources for Leadbelly's Life. An interview with a black reporter: Will people see Leadbelly rather than black stud films? What he hopes to accomplish for recognition of Leadbelly's achievements. Will he make more historical biographical films, Benefit of Leadbelly for our people.